Previously on Transformers: Prime
在上一集里
It is best that you three remain under our watch.
你们三个最好接受我们的监护
Gaze upon Dark Dnergon.
“将得黑暗能量”！
Legend tells that it holds the power to... revive the dead.
传说它威力无比 甚至能…起死回生
Cliffjumper's signal pop back online.
飞过山的信号又出现了
Let's find Cliffjumper.
我们去找飞过山
Cliff!
飞过山！
What is this?
这是什么？
Don't know. Cliff was covered in it.
不知道 飞过山浑身上下都是这东西
Wait! Lord Megatron,
等等！威震天陛下！
you do not know what it will do!
您不知道会有什么后果！
Tighten your grip, Jack.
抓紧了 杰克
Thought you might actually enjoy the ride if you weren't getting shot at.
如果没有人追杀 你可能会感觉好一点
Oh, bring it!
噢 那就来吧！
Ready? Set...
准备好了？开始！
Miko, I'm supposed to be protecting you.
神子 我的职责是保护你
Bulkhead, I'm strapped tight inside ten tons of metal muscle.
隔板 我待在十吨重的钢筋铁骨里面
I'm protected.
万无一失
No fair, Bumblebee,
不公平 大黄蜂
you've been driving a lot longer than I have.
你的驾龄比我长多了
Thank goodness for peace and quiet.
总算安静下来了
House guests can be such a bother.
我们的客人还真难缠
What?
这是？
Optimus?
擎天柱？
I needed that!
那个我还有用呐！
Stay broken!
别想翻身！
Now, what could have caused that?!
那东西是什么来头？
I have a grave suspicion, Ratchet.
我有个不详的预感 救护车
Dark Energon.
黑暗能量
It's as if the blood of Unicron the Destroyer
“破坏者”宇宙大帝之血
flows through my veins.
好像流遍了我浑身的经脉
As if I hear his very thoughts.
我好像感受到他的思想了
I now know what I must do.
我现在知道该怎么做了
Quit grovelling,
别装可怜
and wait my command!
等我发令吧！
Soundwave!
声波！
I fear that when our master reached for the stars,
我怀疑 我们的主人去摘星的时候
he came down with a touch of... space madness.
感染上了某种…太空疯狂症
Lord Megatron has not been having sound judgement since his return.
威震天陛下自从回归后 一直没有做出正确的判断
Increase global surveillance!
加强全球监控！
"Quit grovelling,
“别装可怜”
and wait my command!"
“等我发令吧！”
I'm not deaf!
我不是聋子！
But if Optimus Prime lives,
但如果擎天柱真的还活着
I believe it is in Lord Megatron's best interest
我相信 如果我们能把他干掉
that we insure his enemy's destruction.
威震天陛下会龙颜大悦的
If the residual Arcee found on Cliffjumper
如果阿尔茜从飞过山身上取得的残留物
it would stand a reason that the very same substance brought Cliffjumper back from the dead.
那就是说 同样的物质也能让飞过山起死回生
That would account for his life signal inexplicably coming back online,
他的生命信号突然出现 也能说得通了
but Dark Energon?
可是…那会是黑暗能量吗？
It's so scarce as to be virtually non-existent.
那东西非常罕见 几乎搜索不到
What would it be doing on earth?
它怎么会在地球上出现呢？
It was transported by Megatron.
它是被威震天带来的
For what purpose?
他目的何在？
To conquer this planet
召集一支不死大军
by raising an army of the undead.
征服这个星球
I mean, where on this world
我是说 在这个星球上
would he find that many Cybertronian dead?
哪有那么多塞博特恩星人的尸体啊？
That was awesome.
帅呆了
Can we go again?
我们能再玩儿一次吗？
S-weet!
爽啊！
Sorry,
对不起
must have left that in the backseat.
一定是我丢在后座上的
Autobots, prepare to...
汽车人 准备…
Roll out?
出发？
Remain here.
坚守岗位
Ratchet, you'll come with me.
救护车 跟我来
Arcee, we'll be outside communications range for some time.
阿尔茜 我们会暂时中断联络信号
So I'm putting you in charge.
你来接管基地
Dude, you're biggest.
哥们儿 你个头最大
You should be the boss.
你该当老大
Umm, he... never picks me.
呃 他…从不选我
Optimus, with all due respect,
擎天柱 恕我直言
playing bodyguard is one thing, baby-sitting is another.
做保镖是一回事 看孩子是另一回事
Besides, Ratchet hasn't been in the field since the war.
还有 战后救护车根本没出过基地
My pistons might be rusty,
我的活塞可能有点生锈
but my hearing is sharp as ever.
但我听得很清楚
For the moment, it's only reconnaissance.
这次嘛 只是侦察
Then why do I hear an edge in your voice?
那你的声音怎么有点不安？
Arcee, much has changed in the last 24 hours.
阿尔茜 过去的24小时里发生了很多变化
And we all need to adapt.
我们都需要去适应
Ratchet, bridge us out.
救护车 把我们传送走
Okay, chief, so...
好的 老大 那…
what's on the activities list?
有什么活动？
I'm going on patrol.
我去巡逻
But Optimus told us to stay.
但大哥叫我们呆在这里
When you're in charge, you can call the shots.
你当头儿时 你就说了算
Bee, with me.
小蜂 跟我来
Bulkhead, you're in charge.
隔板 你来当家
So, eh... what's on the activities list?
那…有什么活动？
How about... band practice?!
我们来…乐队排练吧！
But we're not a band.
可我们不是乐手啊
Why so ambisocial? Come on, Raf,
别这么不近人情 来吧 拉夫
you play anything?
你带了什么？
Laptop ensembles, good. Jack?
电脑套装 很好 杰克？
I... sometimes mess around on the harmonica.
我…只是有时候玩玩口琴
Do I look like I do country?
我像玩乡村音乐的吗？
Just cover yourself in fake blood
往身上涂些假血
and jump around screaming.
然后边跳边尖叫
Bulkhead, precaution.
隔板 注意
Look over big industrial sound.
重型音效来了
DIY, we're a band.
自力更生 乐队组成
You just got to learn the songs.
你们最好学学那些歌
This one is a ballad.
这首是民谣
"My fist your face"
《我的拳你的脸》（史密斯飞船乐队）
Come on, you can't handle the raw power?
不是吧 你受不了这种原生力量？
Proximity sensor. Quick, hide!
近程传感器 快藏起来！
Prime!
擎天柱！
Agent Fowler, ugh, he's not here.
福勒探员 呃 大哥不在
Nobody's here.
这儿没有人
Except me, of course.
除了我以外
Well, where did he go?
那他去哪儿了？
Wait, don't tell me. He's out pancaking a mini mall.
等等 别告诉我 他在糟蹋一个小商场
Now, I don't know what language your bots speak on your planet,
我不管你们汽车人在自己的星球上说什么语言
but Prime promised you will handle the Decepticons.
但擎天柱承诺过 你们会搞定霸天虎
And blowing a crater in the middle of Nebraska
在内布拉斯加州炸出个大弹坑
is not what the word "handle" means in English.
可不是“搞定”的意思
So you tell Prime...
你给我告诉擎天柱…
Since when do you bots electric?
你们什么时候开始用电驱动了？
Hey, how are you doing?
嘿 你好吗？
Contact with civilians.
有生人介入
Team Prime has really gone off book this time.
领袖卫队这次太不像话了
Wait, don't tell me. You're running a day-care center?
等等 别告诉我你们在办托儿所吗？
Okay...
好吧…
Uh, we're... interns.
我们是…实习生
Student interns.
在校实习生
Earning extra credit in the auto shop.
要赚外快去买汽车
Robotics.
买机器人
Ok. Let's move.
好 我们走
I'm taking all three of you to federal custody.
我会把你们三个带到联邦拘留所
That's for your own protection.
为了你们的自身安全
We're protecting them.
他们的安全由我们保护
Is that so?
真的吗？
Well, maybe you can explain that to my superiors at the Pentagon.
那你可以向我在五角大楼的上司们解释
Don't use that phone, it's...
别用那个电话 它…
out of order.
坏了
This isn't over, big foot. Not by a long shot.
这不算完 大脚 走着瞧
Optimus, what do we hope to find here?
擎天柱 我们来这儿要找什么？
The site of the largest Cybertronian battlefield in this galaxy.
这是塞博特恩战争在银河系中最大的战场
On Earth?
在地球上？
You must be joking!
你在开玩笑吧！
Do you recall the period late in the war,
你还记得战争的末期吗？
when both sides began hiding their energon spoils off world?
双方都把找到的能量藏在外星球
Of course, it's the reason energon deposits exist on planet such as this one.
当然记得 所以在这样的星球上会有能量矿
It is also the reason battles came to be waged on planet such as this one.
正是如此 这样的星球上才会有战争
And I fear Megatron's memory is as long as history.
我担心 威震天会知道一些很久远的事情
Sir, Agent Fowler.
长官 我是福勒探员
We have a situation.
有情况
I'm in route from the Autobot base.
我刚从汽车人基地出来
I'll brief you in person.
我会亲自向您汇报
"Agent Fowler."
“我是福勒探员”
"I'm in route from the Autobot base."
“我刚从汽车人基地出来”
"I'll brief you in person."
“我会亲自向您汇报”
Autobot base...
汽车人基地啊…
human's always the weak link.
人类永远是弱点所在
Fetch me this Fowler
把这个福勒给我带来
so that he may brief us instead.
让他给我们做个汇报
Hey, big bird, I'm flying here.
嘿 大鸟 别打扰我开飞机
What in Uncle Sam's beard?
这是什么鬼东西？
First, the freeways aren't safe,
先是高速公路不安全
now air travel?
现在轮到天上了？
You wanna dance, Con?
你想跳舞吗 虎子？
I'll lead!
我来领舞！
Never an Autobot around when you actually need one.
真正需要汽车人的时候 没一个靠谱的
My ears!
我的耳朵！
It's an SOS,
是求救信号
from Fowler.
福勒发的
Did you trace it?
你追踪到了吗？
Location scan wasn't complete.
方位扫描无法完成
Oh, well.
管他呢
"Oh, well",
“管他呢”？
seriously?
不是吧？
Fowler's a jerk.
福勒是个混蛋
And Agent Fowler knows your location...
福勒探员知道你们的位置…
And did we not just witness how fast Fowler backs down from a bot?
我们刚才也看见了 福勒在他们面前毫无还手之力
The Cons will totally make him squeal.
虎子们肯定会给他用酷刑的
But we lost the transmission.
可我们失去联系了
Fowler could be anywhere.
福勒有可能在任何地方
Maybe I can narrow it down.
我或许能把范围缩小
About five years ago, the government started micro-chipping their agents.
大约五年前 政府开始在探员身上植入晶片
You know, like owners do with pets.
就像主人对待宠物一样
What? I saw it on TV.
怎么了？我在电视上见过
Anyway, if I can hack into the Fed's main frame,
总之 如果我能入侵联邦政府的主机
maybe I can pinpoint Fowler's coordinates.
就可能找到福勒的坐标
You know how to hack?
你还是黑客呐？
But you're like... two years old.
可你才…两岁啊
Twelve, and a quarter.
十二岁…零三个月
Welcome,
欢迎你
Agent Fowler.
福勒探员
Autobot?
汽车人？
That one of them coin-operated
那些投币式的洗车机器？
Oh, so that's how it's going to be?
噢 原来你吃硬不吃软
Apparently, no one has told you I have no appreciation for human humor.
看来没人告诉过你 我不喜欢人类的幽默感
Make our guest comfortable.
好好招待我们的客人
Latitude 39.5бу, longitude 116.9бу.
北纬39.5°西经116.9°
Ok, wait here.
好 在这儿等着
Oh, don't break up the band!
噢 乐队不能散啊！
Ugh, Jack, you're in charge.
呃 杰克 你来当家
Guess we three have the run of the place.
看来我们三个可以为所欲为了
Miko?
神子？
Fowler?
福勒？
The whole Decepticon ship-bay.
一整窝的霸天虎
Alright,
好了
what's the plan?
有什么计划？
Miko!
神子！
Oh, unwise.
噢 搞砸了
Miko, get down!
神子 趴下！
Hold him still!
把他按住！
Miko, look away!
神子 别看！
But...
- 但… - 把头扭过去！
Arcee, Bumblebee, do you read?
阿尔茜 大黄蜂 你们收到了吗？
Loud and clear, Bulkhead.
很清楚 隔板
I have a situation.
我这儿有点情况
Bulkhead, they're children,
隔板 他们是孩子
humans. Just do whatever.
是人类 随便点
You're where?
你在哪儿？
She's where?!
她在哪儿？
What should we do?
我们怎么办？
Bulkhead may not even realize that she followed him.
隔板可能还不知道 她也去了
Miko hasn't seen the Cons in action like we have.
神子和我们不一样 她没见过虎子的行动
She has no idea.
她一无所知
Those are the coordinates,
坐标还锁定在他们的目的地
Umm, you're in charge.
呃 你来当家
In charge of who?
当谁的家？
Arcee to base, come in.
阿尔茜呼叫基地 回话
Jack? Listen up, we need you to bridge us back.
杰克 听着 你得把我们传送回去
Hello?
喂？
Bumblebee, metal to the pedal.
大黄蜂 全速出发
Agent Fowler, I have one simple request
福勒探员 我有一个简单的请求
that will save your family the pain of grieving.
可以让你的家人免遭痛苦
Tell me the location of the Autobot base.
告诉我汽车人基地的位置
No problem.
没问题
But I need to ask you something first.
但我先要问问你
Yes, I'm listening.
说吧 我听着呢
I got an issue with the customer service around here.
我对这里的客户服务不太满意
Could I speak to the manager?
我可以跟经理谈谈吗？
I make the decisions here.
我说的话就是圣旨
I am in charge!!
这儿我说了算！
Bring the prod.
把能量棍拿来
What's taking Arcee and Bumblebee?
阿尔茜和大黄蜂怎么还没来？
Dude, the Cons could be putting the clamps on Fowler right now.
哥们儿 虎子可能正给福勒上大刑呢
Let's just storm the joint.
我们干脆冲过去得了
Uhh, they're here.
他们来了
Why don't those guys hang with their own bots?
他们怎么不跟自己的搭档玩儿？
This is our one-on-one time.
现在是我们的二人世界
You there!
你们俩！
- Scrap.
- 糟了
I ask nicely one last time:
我再客气地问你最后一次
the Autobot base!
汽车人基地在哪儿？
Sure thing, buddy.
没问题 老兄
Right after you eat my star spangle shorts!
可你得先吃掉我的小星星短裤！
As I imagined,
跟我想的一样
energon and human nerval systems don't mix.
能量和人类神经系统相互排斥
For the first time in my life, Optimus, I had hoped that you were wrong.
擎天柱 我这辈子第一次希望你是错的
Optimus, been well?
擎天柱 你还好吗？
I see you brought your trusty watchdog.
你把那条忠心的看门狗也带来了
I will certainly be convalesce in the scrapyard by now.
我还以为他在废料场里养老呢
Why don't you invite him down here for a chat?
你干嘛不叫他下来谈谈呢？
I know why you're here, Megatron.
我知道你为什么来这里 威震天
Hardly a surprise, Optimus.
这难不住你 擎天柱
After all, you and I have been at this a long time.
毕竟 我们已经相处这么久了
And your time has come to an end.
而你的大限快要到了
Rise, my army!
觉醒吧 我的战士们！
By the Allspark!
我的火种源啊！
Behold, the power of Dark Energon!
请看 这就是传说中的…黑暗能量！